字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：木浅薰 王大可 杨爱菜 Reginamoon 小暴徒 想名字好难
翻译：HOLA 某羽 Timothy  校对：油炸电风扇   木浅薰
时间轴：壬虚浪影  倩倩  Spohy
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第一集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
听着他的总结陈词
Listening to his closing argument,
我自己差点都想放他一马了
I almost want to let him go myself,
唯独有一个问题  他是个骗子
except for one thing-- He's a liar.
他觉得自己不用和你们遵守一样的规矩
He thinks he doesn't have to play by the same rules.
但我们知道他应该
But we know he does.
-你做了什么  -我认罪了
- What did you do? - I pled guilty.
如果你以为我会让你这么做
If you think I'm gonna let you do this,
你就是疯了
you're out of your goddamn mind.
他是为了救律所达成协议
He cut a deal to save this firm.
他是为了不让我们进监狱达成协议
He cut a deal to keep us from going to prison.
把已经想走的人给伊凡
We give Evan people who already want to go,
我给安妮塔・吉布斯凶手名单交换迈克
and I give Anita Gibbs murderers in exchange for Mike.
如果没效果然后我们什么都没了呢
And what if it doesn't work and we lose everything?
那就这样了  但如果没尽力救他  我们是怎样的人
Then we do. But if we don't try to save him, who are we?
达成协议
Make the deal.
我不会让你因为
I am not letting you go to prison
我犯下的罪责进监狱
for a crime that I committed.
我也不能在你会被判无罪的情况下进监狱
I'm not letting you go when you're gonna be found innocent!
你究竟为何要骗我
Why the hell would you lie to me?
因为真相会击垮你
'Cause the truth would've broken you.
你知道吗  哈维
You know what, Harvey?
你如果想参加我的婚礼  告诉我
You want to come to my wedding, you let me know.
我不能再什么都替你做了
I'm not trying to take your place anymore.
我要让你做好准备  因为你太弱了
I'm trying to get you ready because you're weak.
-哈维  我不弱  -那好  打我啊
- Harvey, I am not weak. - Yeah? Well, hit me.
这就是你想要的吗
Is this what you want?
想要我恨你  想要我对你这样做吗
That I hate you and that you made me do this?
我们因为你而失去一切
We lose everything because of you!
我不是说我不想结婚
I am not saying that I don't want to get married.
你去读完法学院
You go finish law school.
然后  两年后我出来
And then in two years, when I get out,
如果你还想嫁给我
if you still want to marry me...
都走了
They're all gone.
在里面多加小心  迈克
Watch your back in there, Mike.
我会的
I will.
所有犯人的起床时间是早晨六点
General wake-up for all inmates is at 6:00 A.M.
那时你要站在床边
You will be standing next to your bed at that time.
如果没有  将会被处罚
If you are not, you will face disciplinary action.
每24小时至少会
At least five inmate counts
随机清点五次人数
will be held during each 24-hour period at random times.
每次清点人数时你要立正站好
You will stand still during every one of those counts.
如果没有  将会被处罚
If you are not, you will face disciplinary action.
如果你想进食可以在规定时间内就餐
You will be at meals on time if you want to eat.
不管有任何情况  你都需要按时上工
You will be at work on time, no matter what.
你必须让你的牢房保持清洁与整齐
You will keep your cell in a clean and sanitary condition.
如果你无法做到上述任何一点  将会
If you fail in any of these areas, you will face...
被处罚
Disciplinary action.
很好  你学得很快
Good. You're getting the picture.
能不能告诉我惩罚是什么
Do you mind if I ask what disciplinary action means?
既然你有种问
Since you got the balls to ask that,
我很确定你很快就会知道
I'm sure you're gonna find out soon enough.
-这是干什么用的  -你觉得呢
- What's this for? - What do you think it's for?
脱光衣服  把所有东西都塞进这个袋子
Strip naked, put everything you own inside that bag,
然后跟我走
then follow me.
哈维  你怎么在这
Harvey, what are you doing here?
我来告诉你我把他送过去了
I came to let you know that I dropped him off,
他的状态已经算不错了
and, um, he looks as good as he could look.
我认为他会没事的
And I think he's gonna be okay.
谢谢你
I appreciate that.
但你完全可以在电话里告诉我这些
But you could have told me that over the phone.
所以你到底来干什么的
So what are you really doing here?
我想他
I miss him.
我也想他
I miss him too.
你要去哪
Where the hell are you going?
你觉得我要去哪
Where do you think I'm going?
-我要回家  路易  -听着  你还不懂吗
- I'm going home, Louis. - Look, don't you get it?
他们都走了  一个都不剩
They're all gone-- every single one of them.
是啊  我们已经知道了
Yeah, well, we knew that already.
不  我觉得你还没明白
No, no, I don't think you understand.
我不只是说合伙人们
I'm not just talking about the partners.
我是说每个人  从会计
I'm talking about everyone, from the accountants
到秘书  还有给我擦鞋的人  唐娜
to the secretaries to the guy who shines my shoes, Donna.
全都走了
All of them, gone.
那你想我做些什么
And what exactly do you want me to do about it?
我想让你给哈维打电话
I want you to get Harvey on the goddamn phone.
-我不会那么做的  -为什么
- Well, I'm not gonna do that. - Why not?
因为今晚不适合给他打电话
Because tonight's not the night to call Harvey.
为什么  因为迈克
Why, because of Mike?
我不知道你们发现没有  但迈克已经走了
I don't know if you've noticed, but Mike is gone,
和所有的人一起
along with everybody else.
如果我们今晚想不出对策
And if we don't figure something out by tonight,
我们就会一无所有
we are gonna be left with nothing.
我没有说不想对策  路易
I didn't say we weren't gonna figure something out, Louis.
我只是说不找哈维
I said we're not calling Harvey.
那我们要做什么
Well, then what the hell are we gonna do?
现在我要回我的办公室
Right now I'm gonna go to my office
给自己来一杯
and fix myself a goddamn drink.
我第一次见他吗
The first time I met him?
你觉得我会怎么想  我
What do you think I thought? I...
我认为他是个白痴
I thought he was an idiot.
在他进门面试不到十秒
Imagine how I felt
就从他的公文包里掉出来一堆大麻
when a bunch of weed spilled out of his briefcase
想象一下我当时的感受
ten seconds after he walked into his interview.
我知道  你吓坏了  拿起电话
I know. You were so horrified, you got on the phone,
然后报了警
and you called the police.
等等  你没这么做
No, wait. You didn't do that.
你给了那个白痴一份工作
You offered the idiot a job.
那是因为听完他的故事
That's because after I heard his story,
我才知道他原来不是个白痴
I knew he wasn't an idiot after all.
而那一早上过去
And I knew by the end of that first morning
我就知道他和我认识的人都不一样
that he wasn't like anyone I'd ever met,
要是我不小心  就会陷入大麻烦
and that if I wasn't careful, I was gonna be in trouble.
-敬麻烦  -敬麻烦
- To trouble. - To trouble.
瞧瞧  路易给我留言了
Look at that. Louis left me a voice mail.
我不明白  你好像还很高兴
I don't understand. You seem happy about that.
因为我最喜欢的消遣之一
That's because one of my favorite pastimes
就是听路易的留言
is to listen to one of Louis's messages.
要是他在郁闷呢
What if he's upset about something?
他永远都在郁闷
He's always upset about something.
所以听他的留言
That's why one of my favorite pastimes
才是我最喜欢的消遣之一
is to listen to one of Louis's messages.
该死的哈维  给我接电话
Damn it, Harvey, pick up the goddamn phone,
因为整个律所人去楼空了
because this entire firm is a ghost town,
我是很遗憾迈克进了监狱
and I'm sorry Mike's in prison,
但如果我们不想出对策
but if we don't figure something out,
你和你的小跟班的这次壮举
what you and your little sidekick did
就是我们的落幕了
is gonna be the end of us.
还有别给我说什么今晚不合适的鬼话
And don't give me some bullshit about tonight isn't the time,
因为
because--
我得走了
I got to go.
我知道  我也去
Yeah, I know. I'm coming with you.
瑞秋  你听到路易的话了
Rachel, you heard what Louis said.
今晚肯定不会好过  你还是留下吧
This is gonna be a rough night. You need to stay here.
哈维  不管我今晚在哪肯定都不会好过
Harvey, it's gonna be a rough night no matter where I am.
至少如果和你在一起
And at least if I'm with you,
我还可能有机会派上用场
there's a chance that I could be of some use.
那你最好穿衣服  我们时间不多
You better get your coat, because we don't have much time.
然后呢
Now what?
然后穿衣服  等着
Now you get dressed, and you wait.
还想再喝点什么吗
Would you like some more drinks?
要不要碟开胃菜  或者松露薯条
Can I offer you an appetizer, maybe some truffle fries,
还是我们可以谈谈工作了
or are we allowed to talk business now?
好吧  路易  既然是你的建议让我们
All right, Louis, what do you think we should do,
落到了这个境地
since it was your recommendation
那你认为我们现在该怎么做
that landed us in this mess in the first place?
我当时那么建议是因为那是最后一个
I recommended that because it was a last-ditch effort
避免迈克牢狱之灾的办法
to get Mike out of prison.
你也说了我们只有一半合伙人会投靠
And you also said we'd only lose 50%
伊凡・施密斯
of our partners to Evan Smith.
我怎么能知道她有本事
How could I have known that she had the capacity
招走一半多呢
to bring on more than that?
你还不懂吗  其他人没有投靠伊凡・施密斯
Don't you get it? The rest didn't go to Evan Smith.
他们只是离开了这里去了别处
They just walked the hell out and went somewhere else.
那我们可以告他们
Then we can sue their asses.
哪里有律师  有资源  有钱告
With what lawyers, what resources, and what money?
因为你可能还没注意到
Because I don't know if you noticed,
但我们律所已经因为你的建议被掏空了
but this firm has been gutted because of your recommendation.
不  杰西卡  它是因为我的建议被掏空的
No, Jessica, it was gutted because of mine.
该死的  路易  我说了让你别找他的
Damn it, Louis. I told you not to call him.
我还是找了  因为他也是合伙人
Well, I did. Because he's a partner,
而且如他所说  提出免除竞业条款的
and like he just said, he was the one
本来就是他
who wanted to sever the noncompetes in the first place.
没错  路易  是我
You're right, Louis. I did.
但我不是来
But I didn't come down here
确认哈维该负责任的
to play Pin the Blame on the Harvey.
我来是为了想办法解决问题
I came down here to figure out what the hell we're gonna do.
那就解决啊
Then let's get to it.
-有事吗  -抱歉打扰了
- May I help you? - Oh, I'm sorry to interrupt,
但前台没有人
but there was no one at reception,
这是您点的餐
and I have your order here.
你逗我呢吧
You got to be kidding me.
你说有急事把我叫来
You call me down here for an emergency,
居然还有闲情逸致点外卖
and then you take the time to order Chinese food?
我没点外卖  你个白痴
I didn't order anything, asshole.
所以别跟我张牙舞爪的
So you crouch your tiger, hide your dragon,
否则我就把你丢出去
or I'm gonna Wang Chung your ass out of here.
路易  镇定  显然这是误会
Louis, calm down. Clearly, there's some mistake.
这律所没人点过外卖
No one at this firm has ordered any food.
我很确定地方没错
Well, I'm pretty sure this is the right place,
因为门上写着杰西卡・皮尔逊
because the name on your door says Jessica Pearson,
这份外卖就是杰西卡・皮尔逊的
and this order is for a Jessica Pearson.
-她就是杰西卡・皮尔逊  -路易
- Yeah this is Jessica Pearson. - Louis!
怎么了
What?
他们知道我其实不是
They know I'm not really here
来送蛋卷的  白痴
to bring you an egg roll, asshole.
我是来送这个的
I'm here to serve you with this.
-那是什么  -集体诉讼
- What is that? - It's a class action.
我们因为迈克・罗斯接触过的所有案子被告了
We're being sued for every case Mike Ross has ever touched.
所以他们才跑光了
That's why they all left.
他们知道会有这事  所以都离开了
They knew this was coming, and they got out
这样他们就能说
so they could all have it on record
诉讼发生时他们已经离开公司了
that they were gone before the suit came down.
那我们需要知道是谁告诉他们的
Then we need to know who the hell tipped them off.
谁说的都不重要
It doesn't matter who tipped them off.
重要的是  如果我们输了
What matters is, if we lose this suit,
绝对付不起罚金
we can't handle the money.
他们要多少
How much are they suing us for?
-1个亿  -该死的
- $100 million. - God damn it.
我们得把那些合伙人找回来
We need to get those partners back.
我说了  找不回来的
I told you, we're never gonna get them back.
而且现在我们连他们去了哪都不知道
And right now we don't even know where they went.
我知道
I do.
你是怎么做到的
How the hell did you pull that off?
因为律师之间不交心
Because lawyers don't talk to lawyers,
但秘书之间常八卦
but secretaries talk to secretaries.
这张表上列明了大家的去向
That is a list of who went where.
好了  我们今晚就需要书面记录
Okay, we need a paper trail tonight--
需要发违约通告
notices of breach of contract--
要正式声明那些合伙人
and we need to get on record
并不是离开了就一了百了了
that those partners aren't off the hook.
现在发违约通告已经晚了
It's too late to send out notices.
我们已经接到诉讼文书了
We already got served with the lawsuit.
他刚刚没有记录时间
He didn't record the time.
唐娜  我桌上的雪茄盒里有五千美元
Donna, there's $5,000 in the cigar box on my desk.
去把它拿过来
Get it now.
等等  你这又是要去哪里
Wait. Where the hell are you going?
我要下楼
I'm going downstairs
告诉那个送文书的他可以把钱全拿走
to tell that server he can have every nickel of it
只要他声明那份文书是两小时之后才送来的
to say he didn't deliver that thing for another two hours.
假设哈维成功
Assuming Harvey doesn't shit the bed,
我们就有两个小时来想办法
we've got two hours to figure out
怎样让这表上的每个合伙人都收到文书
how we're gonna serve every partner on this list.
把表给我
Give me that list.
他们一定会收到文书的
They can consider themselves served,
因为路易・马洛・利特从不在战斗中让步
because Louis Marlowe Litt never backs down from a fight.
丹伯里联邦惩教所
Federal Correctional Institution, Danbury.
您好  我打电话来想问问...
Yes, I'm--I'm calling to check on an--
犯人的情况
Inmate?
没错  他叫迈克・罗斯  他...
Yeah. His name is Michael Ross, and he--
抱歉  女士
I'm sorry, ma'am.
我不能透露犯人的相关信息
I can't give out information regarding inmates.
那您至少能告诉我
Would you at least be able to tell me
他是否被接收入狱了吗
if he's been processed yet?
假如他是自己过来报到的
If he surrendered himself,
那就已经入狱了
then he has been processed.
好的  那意味着他现在在牢房里还是...
Okay, so does that mean that he's in a cell now or--
女士  我是监狱管理员  不是酒店前台
Ma'am, I'm a prison administrator, not a hotel concierge.
我也不知道任意时刻中某个犯人的具体情况
I don't know the whereabouts of any given inmate at any given time.
好吧  那您能告诉我我什么时候能见他吗
Okay, would you be able to tell me when I can see him?
你是他配偶或直系亲属吗
Are you his spouse or immediate family?
不是
No.
那你就得申请  然后等审批
Then you'll have to go through the approval process.
但他没有任何直系亲属了
But he doesn't have any immediate family,
而我是他的未婚妻
and I'm his fiancée.
除非你们有正式的结婚证书
And unless you have a filed marriage certificate,
不然就得等到下个月了
you'll have to wait till next month.
下个月
Next month?
我...我能请问一下您的名字吗
Look, am I--am I allowed to ask your name?
我叫露丝
My name is Ruth.
露丝  迈克和我...
Ruth, Mike and I were...
本来应该今天结婚的  但我们没结成
supposed to be married today, but we weren't.
我忍不住一直想着他
And I can't stop thinking about him,
要是不知道他是否安好
and I'm not gonna be able to sleep
我完全无法入睡
unless I know that he's gonna be okay.
他可是在监狱里啊  女士
He's in prison, ma'am.
这还真不好说
I really couldn't say.
抱歉
I am sorry.
没什么比监狱蓝衣更能让你意识到
Nothing like prison blue to make you realize
人靠衣装这句话是错的  是吧
the clothes don't make the man, huh?
-是克拉克典狱长吗  -我吗
- Warden Clark? - Me?
不是
No.
谁告诉你你会见到典狱长的
Who told you you were going to meet the warden?
没有人  我只是以为...
Uh, no one. I-I just thought--
以为这会和监狱题材的电影一样
That this was going to be like a prison movie.
台词和接下来的海报盖住的洞的梗
都出自《肖申克的救赎》
"爱信上帝信上帝
"Put your trust in the Lord,
但你的贱命是我的了"这类的狗屁
but your ass belongs to me" type shit.
你看过《肖申克的救赎》
You know "Shawshank"?
你当然看过《肖申克的救赎》
Of course you know "Shawshank."
你可是在监狱里工作的
You work in a prison.
不  兄弟  我看过《肖申克的救赎》
No, brother, I know "Shawshank"
是因为这是有史以来最伟大的电影  给
because it's the greatest movie ever made. Here...
这是什么
What's this?
你的心理评估表
Your psychological evaluation.
我什么要进行心理评估
Why do I need a psychological evaluation?
因为联邦监狱系统是这么规定的
Because the federal penitentiary system says you do.
等下我回来的时候  假如镜子上有个洞
Now, when I get back, if there's a hole in the mirror
上面盖着丽塔・海华丝的海报
covered by a Rita Hayworth poster,
我可不会高兴的
I will not be happy.
行了  路易  冷静下来
Okay, Louis, calm down.
你哑了几次火  可能还中风了
You've had a few misfires, possibly had a stroke,
但你可以的
but you can do this.
你输入了有关信息
You've entered the requisite information.
你完美地校准了字体
You calibrated the typeface perfectly.
你现在只需要按下"发送"键
All you have to do is press "send,"
然后那些贱人们就要被"利击"了
and those sons of bitches are about to get Litt the hell up.
-我操你...  -你在干什么
- God damn mother-- - What the hell are you doing?
我只是在排查故障  怎么了
I'm just doing a little troubleshooting. Why?
那可是40万美元的硬件
That is a $400,000 piece of hardware,
你没有权力...
and you have no business even--
等等  你还留在这里干什么
Wait a second. What are you still doing here?
干任何称职的技术人员该干的事
What any IT officer worth his salt would do.
我在维护我们的系统  这样在外界看来
I'm maintaining our system, so it appears we're still
我们还是一个正常运转的律所
a functioning law firm to the outside world.
你能在两小时之内把法律通告
Can you electronically serve legal notice
电子送达给各位合伙人吗
to every partner in the next two hours?
只要你有他们的正式工作地址
As long as you've got their official business addresses,
我两分钟后就能搞定
I can do it in the next two minutes.
正好我手头就有这些信息
Well, it's a good thing I have them right here.
无意冒犯  但我真的比较习惯单干
Um, no offense, but I'm really more of a lone ranger.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你别趴在我身上盯着
I can get this done in a more efficient manner
我的效率更高
without you looking over my shoulder.
我当年看我的第一本《花花公子》时
Well, that's what I told my mother
也是这么和我妈说的
when I looked at my first "Playboy."
当时行不通  现在也行不通
But it didn't happen then, and it's not gonna happen now.
这都无关紧要了  因为...
Well, that doesn't matter because...
我们遇到麻烦了
we have a problem.
所以你的意思是  在这个办公室里
So you're saying, in this office,
一直以来
at any given moment,
都藏着十万美元
there's $100,000 hidden away.
-就是这个意思  -藏在哪里
- That's what I'm saying. - Where?
我才不会告诉你
I'm not telling you.
不管你们两个在忙什么
Whatever the hell you two are in the middle of,
都得停一停了
it's gonna have to wait,
因为尽管秘书之间常八卦
because secretaries may talk to secretaries,
但骗子也专骗傻子
but liars talk to idiots.
路易  你这话是什么意思
Louis, what the hell are you talking about?
我的意思是那个列表纯粹就是扯淡
I'm saying that that list is a bucket of bullshit,
而伟大的唐娜・鲍尔森
and the mighty Donna Paulsen--
完全没搞清楚状况
she doesn't know her ass from her elbow.
说话注意点  路易
Watch yourself, Louis.
我没必要注意  哈维
I don't need to watch myself, Harvey.
我不知道你有留意到没
See, I don't know if you've noticed,
我们可是被人索赔一亿美元
but we're being sued for a $100 million.
合伙人都走了  我们却只能眼睁睁看着
The partners are gone, and we can't stop them.
也许我们不必阻止他们
Maybe we don't have to stop them.
什么意思
What are you saying?
我现在想知道的是咱们加起来有多少身家
What I want to know right now is what we're all worth.
什么  你在说笑吗
What, are you kidding?
你怎么不干脆拿电牛棒捅我菊花呢
Why don't you just jam a cattle prod up my ass?
这样对我伤害还小点
It would be less invasive.
你再乱来
I'll jam my fist in your face
我就一拳打到你脸上
if you don't start getting with the program.
又来了  暴力解决一切  死性不改
There you go, resorting to violence, like you always do.
就因为你不想承认这整件事
Because you don't want to admit this whole thing
都是因你的错而起
is your fault in the first place.
我的错吗  要不是我把迈克招进来
My fault? If I hadn't brought Mike in,
你到现在还只能跟个初级合伙人一样
you'd still be here sniveling around
在这里哭天喊地
like a goddamn junior partner.
要不是我把唐娜送回给你
And if I hadn't given Donna back to you,
你的恐慌症到现在都好不了
you'd still be having panic attacks
就跟个娘们一样
like a goddamn little girl.
-路易  -你这个狗屁东西
- Louis! - You smug son of a bitch.
够了
That's enough!
我刚目送自己心爱的男人入狱
I just watched the man that I love go to prison
好让你们不受牵连
so none of you have to.
结果现在五分钟不到...
And it hasn't been five minutes...
你们就已经吵得不可开交了
And you're already ripping each other apart.
-瑞秋...  -让我说完
- Rachel... - Let me finish.
我本来想今晚一个人静静
I thought I wanted to be alone tonight.
但我想还是算了
And then I realized that I didn't,
因为我要和家人在一起
because I wanted to be with my family.
但不说平时  如果今晚你们还不能
But if you can't keep it together tonight...
团结在一起  那我想...
of all nights, then as far as I'm concerned...
你们都可以下地狱了
you can all rot in hell.
我来把她说不出口的话给说了吧
Well, I'm gonna say what she won't.
这都是你的错
This is all on you.
路易  这里也是我今晚最不想来的地方
Louis, this is the last place I wanted to be tonight too,
但我还是回来拯救我的律所了
but I came back here to save my firm anyway.
如果你还是死性不改
But if you're gonna be the same old Louis
还是要跟我像平时一样闹
and we're going to do the same old dance,
那你也可以抱着律所一起下地狱了
then maybe you and this firm can both go rot in hell.
路易  我不想听你说那话
Louis, I don't want to hear it.
很好  因为我也不是要来说那话的
Well, that's good, because I'm not here to say it.
你是说你专门跑下来
Are you saying you didn't come down here
不是为了跟我抱怨哈维的吗
to tell me Harvey can go to hell?
我跑下来是为了跟你说
I'm saying I came down here to tell you,
如果哈维想一走了之的话...
if Harvey wants to go...
-我们就放他走吧  -路易
- we should let him. - Louis.
杰西卡  你曾经跟我说过
Jessica, you once told me,
无论发生什么事情
no matter what happens,
皮尔逊会一直把利特看作自己的合伙人
Pearson will always consider Litt her partner,
这就意味着不管哈维如何...
which means whatever happens with Harvey...
我们都会同舟共济
we can do this together.
你怎么看  你我联手
What do you say-- you and me?
皮尔逊-利特律师事务所
Pearson Litt.
你不愿意
You say no.
-不是的  路易  -我早该知道了
- No, Louis-- - I should have known.
你一直都不喜欢我
You never wanted me.
你想要的只有那珍贵无比的哈维
All you ever wanted was your precious Harvey.
路易  你根本不知道我想要什么
Louis, you have no idea what I want.
我会犹豫也不是因为你
And my hesitation has nothing to do with you.
那到底是怎么回事
Then what exactly does it have to do with?
路易...
Louis...
一直以来我都在不惜一切代价
I have put everything I have into keeping this firm afloat
保护着这家律所
for as long as I can remember.
但你看看这里
Well, now look around you.
这艘船不是岌岌可危  而是已经沉到海底了
The ship isn't sinking. It sunk.
我都不知道自己是否有能力
And I don't know if I have it in me
把它从大洋深处
to pull it back up
给捞回来了
from the bottom of the ocean.
你终于回来了
Finally.
什么
Excuse me?
他们三小时前就跑过来把那东西给拿走了
They came and took that thing away three hours ago.
而我却只能坐在这里玩自己的手指
I've been sitting here twiddling my thumbs ever since.
你不是在玩手指
You were not twiddling your thumbs.
你是在等我浏览测试结果
You were waiting for me to go over the results of that thing.
然而从结果看  你就是在胡扯
And the results are you are full of shit.
-你说什么  -你没听错
- Excuse me? - You heard me.
每个问题我都是如实作答的
I answered every one of those questions honestly.
我没说你不诚实
I didn't say you didn't.
既然如此  我想你不怎么清楚状况
Well, in that case, I guess you didn't get the memo.
这监狱里关的都是骗子
We're in a prison filled with con men.
所有人的话都不可信
Everyone here is full of shit.
但你和他们之间的区别在于
And the difference between you and them
他们知道自己在说谎
is they know they are.
你的话我已经听不懂了
What does that even mean?
意思就是  他们知道自己没有耐心
It means that they know they don't have the patience
合法赚取到自己想要的东西
to earn what they want,
因此才去从别人手中去偷
and that's why they go out and steal it from other people.
你就是因为这个才冷落我这么久
So that's why you left me in here all that time,
就是为了证明我没有耐心
just to prove that I have no patience.
第二项测试  自恋倾向
Evaluation number two, narcissistic tendencies.
世界不是围着你转的
The world does not revolve around you.
我没必要听你说这番话
You know what? I don't have to listen to this.
没错  因为我今天的工作结束了
No, you don't, because my day is done.
我要回到家里
And I'm going to go home,
给自己倒杯冰镇啤酒
pour myself a cold beer
然而你只能待在
while you get settled in cell 42
D区南边的42号牢房里
on the south end of D block.
我懂了
Yeah, I get it.
我不再是那个迈克・罗斯了
I'm no longer Mike Ross.
我只是编号为53296的囚犯
I'm just inmate number 53296.
不  你依旧是迈克・罗斯
No, you're still Mike Ross.
而我的任务是让你在刑满释放时
But my job is to help you become a better version of him
成为一个更好的你
when you leave than when you came in.
如果你相信我  就有可能实现
And if you trust me, that just might happen.
相信你
Trust you?
你上次进来时装作跟我跟我同一战线的样子
You came in here before acting like you were on my side.
我们来把话说清楚
Let's get one thing straight.
我什么都没有装
I didn't act anything.
你步伐轻盈地走进来
You waltzed in here thinking
以为这会跟监狱电影的桥段一样
this was gonna be like some prison movie.
然而现实并非如此  接受现实吧
Well, it's not, so get that through your head.
这不是监狱电影  哥们
It's not a movie, brother.
是监狱
It's just prison.
皮尔森-斯佩克特-利特
律师事务所
你敢按那按钮
Don't you dare push that button.
哈维  你今晚不能走
You're not leaving, Harvey, not tonight.
-不  我要走  -如果你真的要走
- Yes, I am. - Well, if you really mean that,
那真是让我大失所望
then you're not the man I thought you were.
你说什么
What did you just say to me?
我是说  隐藏在这套昂贵的西装
I said that underneath that expensive suit
和完美履历这些光鲜艳丽的外表背后的
and that perfect record is a coward
是一个打算在此生最大战役中当逃兵的懦夫
ready to run from one of the biggest fights of his life.
我没有逃避什么  唐娜
I am not running from anything, Donna,
我现在也不想听你说这些
and I don't need this right now.
不  哈维  这番话就该现在讲给你听
No, Harvey, right now is exactly when you need this,
因为到了明天  一切都来不及了
because tomorrow's gonna be too late.
我知道自己在干什么
I know what I'm doing.
那不妨说出来让我听听
Then why don't you enlighten me?
因为我
Because I, for one,
就十分想知道你在干什么
would love to know exactly what you're doing.
我要回家从此不再回头
I'm gonna go the hell home and never look back.
那明天怎么办
And what about tomorrow?
我不在乎明天会怎样
I don't care about tomorrow.
也许你该为明天担忧了
Well, maybe you should start caring about tomorrow,
否则的话
because if you don't,
三周后你清醒过来
you're gonna wake up three weeks from now,
就会意识到
and you're gonna realize that this
这是你这辈子最大的错误
was the biggest mistake of your life,
你所做的就是在放弃
and all you did was give up
迈克入狱所换来的一切
exactly what Mike went to prison to save.
迈克入狱不是为了挽救这该死的律所
Mike did not go to prison to save this goddamn firm.
没错  哈维  他是为了救我们
No, Harvey, he went to prison to save us.
然而如今你又要抛下我们不管
And now you're walking out on us.
如果你真的要走  那你告诉我
And if you're gonna do that, then tell me,
他的拯救还有何意义
what did he save us for?
我们来把话说清楚
Let's get one thing straight.
你步伐轻盈地走进来
You waltzed in here thinking
以为这会跟监狱电影的桥段一样
this was gonna be like a prison movie.
然而现实并非如此
Well, it's not.
罗斯
Ross.
这不是监狱电影  哥们
It's not a movie, brother.
是监狱
It's just prison.
罗斯
Ross.
听到我说话了吗
Did you hear me?
第一天来就想找不自在吗
We gonna have trouble your first night?
-不想  -那就快进去
- No. - Then get in there.
还有件事...
One more thing...
你今晚不许再出这间牢房了
you're not authorized to leave this cell the rest of the night.
抱歉  杰西卡
Jessica, I'm sorry.
我以前就坐在这个位子
You know, this used to be my desk.
桌子换了  但位置没变
Different desk, same spot.
杰克森坐那  伯恩斯在那个位子
Jackson was there, Burns was there,
克莱曼坐在门旁边
and Kleiman was by the door.
他不喜欢坐门旁边
He hated being by the door.
这几个名字我都没听说过
I don't know any of those names.
因为他们很久前就辞职了
Because they got out a long time ago,
因为不是所有人都喜欢这种生活
because this life isn't for everyone.
而这种生活对某些人来说格外艰辛
And it's harder on some than it is on others.
-我不懂  -我的意思是...
- What are you saying? - I'm saying that...
对于女人来讲  规则是不同的
for women, the rules are different.
你不能和所有人成为朋友
You can't be everyone's friend
邀请他们喝茶  因为
and invite them to tea because...
温柔等于软弱
warm means you're weak.
我不愿意软弱
I wasn't gonna be weak.
但这事的另一面是
But now the flip side to that is,
如果你很坚强  人们会认为你很冷漠
if you're strong, they think you're cold.
所以他们都走了
And that's why they're all gone...
因为他们把我看作
because they see me as...
一个毫无情感  控制欲很强的人
as unfeeling and manipulative.
我已经受够
I'm tired of it.
他们错了
Well, they're wrong.
你之所以这么说是因为
You're just saying that
你看到了我现在这个样子
because you're seeing me like this.
不  与这件事无关
No, that has nothing to do with it.
我父亲告诉我
My dad told me
他今天来教堂的唯一原因就是
that the only reason he came to the church today
你告诉他如果他不去
was because you told him if he didn't,
他就将永远失去我
he would lose me forever.
你那么做并不是
And you didn't do that
因为你想控制什么局面
because you were trying to manipulate some situation.
你那么做因为你在乎
You did it because you care.
也正因为你那样做了
And because you did it,
我会永远忠诚于你
I will be loyal to you forever.
有什么事吗  哈维
What can I do for you, Harvey?
我来是想跟你说对不起
I came to tell you that I'm sorry.
你确实该说
You should be.
我知道
I know.
那你是要臭骂我一顿
So you gonna give me a tongue lashing,
还是来想办法逃脱眼下的困境
or you want to figure out how we can get out of this jackpot?
我认为现在你和我还有路易
I think that right now you and me and Louis
应该找个屋子抽根烟  和好
should get in a room and smoke a peace pipe.
你说的是我想的那个意思吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
当然了
I sure as hell am.
那这么晚了  我们去哪
And where exactly are we gonna get that shit
能弄到
this late at night?
因为办公室的茶水小弟早就走了
'Cause the coffee cart guy is long gone.
正巧了
It just so happens
有时我就是喜欢自己泡咖啡
I like to brew my own coffee from time to time.
我去喝一杯吧
I'm gonna go get a drink.
那是非法的  你知道
That stuff's illegal, you know.
把那个放下
Put that down.
-对不起  我没有想要  -碰我的东西
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean to-- - Touch my stuff?
真好笑  我可没看见那张照片自己跳到你手上
Funny, I didn't see the picture jump into your hands by itself.
听着  我只是
Look, I was just--
放松  我逗你的
Relax, I'm just giving you shit.
那是我的小侄女  很好的孩子
That's my little nephew-- sweet kid,
跟石头一样没脑
dumb as a box of rocks.
欢迎来到丹伯里  你叫什么
Welcome to Danbury. What's your name?
迈克  迈克・罗斯
Mike. Mike Ross.
弗兰克・加洛
Frank Gallo.
迈克  看来咱俩在很长一段时间里
Well, Mike, looks like we're gonna be sharing
需要共享这个小套间了
this little condo for a while.
想跟我说说你是为什么进来的吗
Feel like telling me what you're in for?
我知道了  你不确定能不能信任我
I get it. You don't know if you can trust me.
事实上  你不能信任这里的任何人
Listen, truth is, you shouldn't trust anybody in here.
只是我刚问你的是你犯了什么事
Except I just asked what you did,
很显然他们已经逮到你了
and they obviously already caught you,
你能有什么损失呢
so what's the harm?
如果没有损失
Well, if there's no harm,
那你为什么不告诉我你为什么进来呢
then why don't you tell me what you're in for?
那说来话长了
That could take a while.
我不知道你是什么情况
I don't know about you,
但我接下来的两年都很闲
but I'm free for the next two years.
小心点
Careful.
你看  你已经告诉我你要呆多久了
See, now you've told me how long you're in for.
开始透露了信息  到最后你就会连
Starts there, ends with you telling me
你是生来贫穷的黑人孩子的底都透露给我
you were born a poor black child.
-你看过《混蛋》  -是啊  你也看过
- You know "The Jerk"? - Yeah, you know "The Jerk"?
我小时候看过很多电影
Yeah, I watched a lot of movies growing up.
我们在这里会看很多电影
We watch a lot of movies in here.
好吧  你想听我的故事
All right, you want to know my story?
那要从我犯事的很久以前开始讲
It starts long before I did what I did,
因为我不是个生来贫穷的黑人孩子
because I wasn't born a poor black child,
但我确实是个贫穷的孩子
but I was born poor,
这也让我非常想变得富有
which made me susceptible to wanting to be rich.
我当然会为我自己考虑
Of course I'm thinking about myself.
怎么  你就不会吗
What, you wouldn't?
拜托  为了救你自己  你都能
Please, you'd throw a giraffe off of Noah's Ark
把诺亚方舟的长颈鹿挤下去
just to save your sorry ass.
没准就是因为你的某个祖先
The world's probably without unicorns
世界上才没有独角兽的  我
because of one of your ancestors, and I--
能让我先说完吗  我的天哪
Will you just let me finish a thought, for God's sake?
路易  你在干什么
Louis? What exactly are you doing?
你看我像是在干什么
Well, what does it look like I'm doing?
我在和我死去秘书的骨灰
I'm having a discussion about the fate of the firm
讨论律所的命运问题
with my dead secretary's ashes.
好吧  既然不是什么过于怪异的事就算了
Well, as long as it's not something weird.
那你们两个在过去的这半个小时又做了什么呢
What exactly have you two been doing the last half hour?
你马上要做的事
The same thing you're about to do.
不可能  我才不会抽大麻
No way, I'm not doing the Mary Jane.
-你会的  -我才不会吞云吐雾
- Yes, you are. - I'm not huffing and puffing.
-路易  这是唯一的方法  -不  我不做违法的事
- Louis, it's the only way. - No, I'm not doing the dirty.
没事的  交给我
It's okay. I got this.
我是说  路易不想抽  也许诺玛想呢
I mean, if Louis doesn't want to smoke it, maybe Norma does.
你敢
Don't you dare.
放松  路易
Relax, Louis.
这又不会害死她
It's not like it's gonna kill her.
哈维  这不是闹着玩的  好吗
Harvey, that is not funny, okay?
你会把她骨灰弄脏的
You're gonna get ashes in her ashes.
那你自己来抽啊
Then why don't you just smoke it yourself?
-灭了火  -就不
- Put that out. - Nope.
倒数三个数我要把这支大麻点了  一
I'm gonna light this joint on the count of one...
-哈维  我告诉你  -二
- Harvey, I'm telling you. - Two...
-哈维  -三
- Harvey! - Three.
你改主意了吗
Did you pull your back out?
把那玩意给我
Give me the goddamn thing.
我了个天
Jesus Christ.
这就是电脑的精髓
That's the thing about computers.
你想删除什么都行
You can delete whatever you want,
但数据永远不会真正消失
but it's never really gone.
如果你没做最后那次交易
So, if you had just stopped one trade sooner,
他们可能永远抓不到你
they might never have even caught you.
没错  我本可以最后三四五次交易都不做
Yeah, I could've stopped five, four, three trades sooner.
都不会抓到我  但你怎么知道什么时候停手
They might not have. But how do you know?
我告诉你什么时候停手
I'll tell you how you know.
当你有了足够的钱
You stop when you have enough money
送你孩子读完大学的时候
to put your kids through college.
是  但读什么样的大学
Yeah, but what college?
如果他们想读医学院呢
And what if they want to go to med school?
如果他们想要一辆车呢
And what if they need a car?
就这样想着想着
And then somewhere along the way,
你不再考虑他们是否需要车
you stop thinking about if they need a car,
转而开始考虑"我需要一辆车"
and you start thinking, "I need a car."
就在这时你被抓了
And that's when you get caught,
因为不管你是否承认
because whether you want to admit it to yourself or not,
你从没在第一时间考虑到他们
you were never thinking about them in first place.
不管你是否考虑到了
And whether you were or weren't,
一旦你开始  便难以收手
once you start, you don't stop.
这真是个精彩的故事  弗兰克
That's one hell of a story, Frank.
是啊  这是监狱
Yeah, well, this is prison.
每人都有个精彩的故事
Everyone's got a hell of a story.
行了  今晚先讲这个故事
Anyway, that's enough for one night.
我要睡觉了
I'm gonna go to bed.
我的故事是源于我奶奶
My story started with my grandmother.
她病了
She was sick,
需要钱
and she needed money...
我找了个办法挣钱给她治病
and I found a way to get it for her.
我了个去
Holy shit.
这玩意简直棒呆了
This is the best thing ever.
我爱死你俩了
I love the both of you so much.
-看你干的好事  -哈维  我们要成功了
- This is your doing. - Harvey, we're making progress.
天哪  这是我吃过的最好吃的蛋卷
Holy shit. This is the best egg roll ever.
老天爷  我要离开这里
Jesus Christ, get me out of here.
真是太爽了
This is so awesome.
自从我得了奥林匹克数学竞赛冠军
I mean, I haven't been this stress-free
并且埃斯特去了减肥夏令营的那一周之后
since I took gold in the Math-lympics
我从没有这么放松过
and Esther went to fat camp in the same week.
埃斯特去过减肥夏令营
Esther went to fat camp?
他们管那个叫小提琴全明星夏令营
They called it Violin All-Stars,
但我们都知道它的真正意思
but we all know what that's code for.
如果你想象她穿着女生校服的样子
And if you so much as picture her in a school-girl outfit.
拜托  路易  我们都觉得挺好的
Come on, Louis, we're all feeling good.
难道你想给我说你从来没有不小心
You telling me you never slipped up
掉进一段不恰当的关系吗
and had an inappropriate relationship?
-路易  我不想知道答案  -有过
- Louis, I do not want to know the answer to that. - I did.
那是我人生中最丢脸的一晚
It was the most shameful night of my life.
-哈维  别问  -你为什么丢脸
- Harvey, don't-- - What exactly was so shameful about it?
她是个律师助理
Well, she was a paralegal,
我和她一起洗泥浴了
and I took mud with her.
我不懂
I don't understand.
你是说你玷污了她的名声
Are you saying you sullied her reputation?
不  我是说我玷污了泥浴
No, I'm saying I sullied the concept of mud.
你到底在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
怎么  我需要用扩音器吗
What, do I need a bullhorn?
我做了一次草率的泥浴
I had a premature muddification.
这是什么鬼意思
What the hell does that mean?
我想我们都明白他的意思了
I think we all know what that means.
意思是我在泥里没克制住激情
It means I couldn't hold my mud.
我还是不懂到底什么意思
I still don't know what that means.
你在泥浴里上大号了
Did you take a shit in the mud?
没有  这太恶心了
No, that's disgusting.
好吧  这个对话有不恶心人的部分吗
Well, what part of this conversation isn't disgusting?
我知道我会后悔问这个的
I know I'm gonna regret asking this.
到底是谁
Who exactly was it?
我不能告诉你
I cannot tell you that information.
那太好了  因为事实上我不...
Okay, good, because the truth is, I don't--
是米西・迪特勒
It was Missy Dietler.
路易  我要问你个问题
Louis, I'm gonna ask you a question.
希望你如实回答
I want you to tell me the truth.
米西・迪特勒知道你没克制住自己吗
Does Missy Dietler know you couldn't hold your mud?
当然不知道
Oh, heavens no.
那个土耳其泥浆厚到
The Turkish silt was thick enough
让她不会感觉到...
to prevent her from feeling it, so...
厚到能掩盖你射完就睡觉吗
Was it thick enough to hide you wanting to go sleep after?
天哪  她知道了
My God, she knew.
我得告诉你  路易  他们都知道
I got news for you, Louis. They always know.
你说的太对了
Oh, you're so right.
真是太对了
You're so right.
她
She--
我需要一刻钟静一静
I need 15 minutes to myself.
就这样
And that's it.
我做了个交易  然后我就到这了
I cut a deal, and now I'm here.
等等
Wait a second.
如果你是个冒牌律师  他们肯定给过你机会
If you're a fake lawyer, they had to give you a chance
把其他人抖出来这样你就不用坐牢了
to turn on someone to get out of it.
他们给了
They did.
所以为什么你没有这样做
So why the hell didn't you do it?
因为这样做的话我的良心会过不去
Because I wouldn't have been able to live with myself.
那外面可有人欠你一个大人情
Somebody out there owes you a lot.
没错
Yeah, well...
但我也欠他很多
I owe him a lot too.
所以
So, what, you're--
你是个好人还是
you're like a-a good guy or something?
我是吗
Am I?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我今天在圣坛抛下了我爱的女人
I left the woman I love at the altar today.
你为什么这样做
Why'd you do that?
因为我不想让她以后后悔
Because I didn't want to chain her to me
现在留在我身边
if there was even the chance that she would regret it.
没错  你就是个好人
Then, yeah, you're a good guy.
谢谢你  弗兰克
Thanks, Frank.
大家都走了的好处之一就是
One thing about everyone being gone...
我们可以在里这想干嘛就干嘛
we got the run of the place.
我从来不知道这里的天花板是这样的
I never knew what the ceiling looked like in here.
我们好像《早餐俱乐部》一样
It's like "The Breakfast Club."
你有过不引用电影的时候吗
Do you ever not quote a movie?
没有  如果你对此有意见的话  亲爱的
No, and you got a problem with that, frankly, my dear,
我一点都不在乎
I don't give a damn.
你就是个笨蛋
You're an idiot.
你觉得路易和我会和好吗
You think Louis is gonna be okay with me now?
我想我们马上就能知道了
I think we're about to find out.
哈维  有关之前我说的
Harvey, what I was saying before...
路易  你不需要说任何话
You don't need to say anything, Louis.
我不会把它告诉任何人的
I'm not gonna tell anyone.
这不是我要说的
That's not what I was gonna say.
那不是唯一的我有过的不恰当关系
It's not the only inappropriate relationship I ever had.
我把你说知道迈克没去过法学院录了下来
I recorded you saying that you knew about Mike,
而且我差点把录音给了安妮塔・吉布斯
and I almost gave it to Anita Gibbs.
-你知道这件事吗  -不知道
- Did you know about this? - No.
但当他试图拉我一起把你交给吉布斯时
But I suspected when he tried to get me
我就有所怀疑了
to turn you in to Gibbs with him.
你是怎么样回复他的要求的
And what exactly was your response to that request?
她说我们没有必要这样做
She said we didn't need to do that,
如果真的到了那一步
and if it came to it,
你会替我们两个顶罪的
you would take the bullet for both of us.
-我会的  -哈维  我很抱歉
- I would have. - I'm sorry, Harvey.
我差点毁了你的生活
I almost ruined your life.
你不需要道歉  路易
You don't need to be sorry, Louis.
事实上是  当我决定录用迈克时
The truth is, I'm the one that ruined all of our lives,
我就成了那个毁了我们生活的人
when I hired Mike.
而且我从未对此向你们道歉
And I never apologized to either one of you for it,
但我现在会了
but I will now.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
所以
So...
我们和好了吗
we good?
我们和好了
We're good.
很好  现在既然你们两人已经和好了
All right, now that the two of you have made peace,
让我们想想该如何打赢这场战争
let's figure out how we're gonna win this war,
就从弄清楚我们有多少战争资金开始
which starts with knowing how much we have in our war chest.
这是什么意思
What exactly does that mean?
意思是  现在是回答
It means it's time
她两小时前问的问题的时候了
to answer the question that she asked two hours ago.
我们到底有多少钱
How much money do we have?
又是这个问题
This again?
路易  今晚经历了这么多事之后
Louis, after everything we've been through tonight,
写下我们各自有多少钱
how hard could it be for us to write down
能有多难呢
how much we're worth right now?
再给我一刻钟静一静
I need another 15 minutes to myself.
-又来  -哈维  让他去吧
- Again? - Aw, Harvey, let him go.
他可能没有我们有钱
He probably doesn't have as much as we do,
这会让他感觉自己很脆弱
and it's a vulnerable thing for him.
很脆弱
"Vulnerable"?
他刚刚才告诉我们他在泥巴里打飞机
He just told us he jerked off in the mud an hour ago.
你不会认为他现在就在那么做吧
You don't think he's gonna do that right now, do you?
根据他告诉我们的
Based on what he told us,
他用不了一刻钟
he doesn't need 15 minutes for that.
你想打电话给她吗
You want to call her?
什么
What?
你的未婚妻  你想打给她吗
Your fiancée, you want to call her?
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我是说我来这儿第一夜时
I'm talking about my first night in here.
我记得当时满脑子想的都是
I remember thinking what I wouldn't give
只要能告诉詹妮弗我很好  我什么都愿意做
to let Jennifer know I was okay.
事情是  我当时不行  但你现在可以
The thing is, I couldn't, but you can.
我以为我们在这不能有手机
I thought we weren't allowed to have phones in here.
嗯  我之前还不被允许做内幕交易呢
Yeah, well, I wasn't allowed to make inside trades either.
但我做了  现在我在监狱里
But I did, and now I'm in here.
他们还能拿我怎么办
What else are they gonna do?
谢谢  但是
Uh, thanks, but...
我只是
I just...
我现在还不能
I just can't right now.
你什么时候想打了  手机就在这
Whenever you want, phone's right here.
试着睡一下吧
Let's try to get some shut-eye, man.
你还好吗
You okay?
到处都是他
He's everywhere.
到处都有他的影子  唐娜
He's all around here, Donna.
我们第一次见面的地方在公司的过道
The first place we met was down the hallway.
我们第一次接吻的地方是在图书馆
And the first time we kissed was in the library.
我在离这50英尺的地方见了他的祖母
And I met his grandmother 50 feet from here.
就在这  他把一切都告诉我了
And right here, he told me the truth.
-瑞秋  -他就站在
- Rachel-- - He was standing
你现在的位置  我当时对他很生气
right where you are, and I was upset with him
为什么我自己都不记得了
about something that I don't even remember.
然后他跟我说他失去了一切
And then he told me that he had lost everyone in his life,
还告诉我他是个冒牌货
and then he told me he was a fraud.
然后我们...
And then we... Mm.
-你会撑过去的  -我知道
- You're gonna get through this. - I know.
我只希望我能见到他
I just wish I could see him.
什么意思  你可以见他啊
What do you mean? You can see him.
我不行  我给监狱打了电话
No, I can't. I called the prison.
你今晚给监狱打了电话
You called the prison tonight?
是的  我想知道他是不是还好
Yes, because I wanted to know if he was okay.
可他们...
And they...
他们什么信息都不给我
they wouldn't give me any information.
我就问了探视的事
So then I asked them about visitation,
可他们说我得等
and they said that I had to wait,
我得进一个名单里  然后...
and I had to get on a list, and--
要多久
How long?
至少一个月
At least a month.
我不知道能说什么
I don't know what to say.
你总是知道该说什么的
You always know what to say.
这次真不知道
Not this time.
抱歉  女士们
Excuse me, ladies.
很抱歉打扰了  但我觉得我们有麻烦
Sorry to interrupt, but I think we might have a problem.
-怎么了  本杰明  -我们被黑客攻击了
- What is it, Benjamin? - We're being hacked.
你写了个很不错的数额嘛
Oh, that's a tidy little sum you got there.
你也不错啊
You're not doing so bad yourself.
是啊  我是不错
No, I am not.
对于两个一无所有的人来说是不错
Not bad for two people that came from nothing.
我不是一无所有  你知道
I didn't come from nothing, and you know it.
写下那个数字肯定感觉还是很不错
Bet it still feels pretty good to write that number down.
那是当然了
Oh, it sure does.
你还有点嗨呢  是吗
You're still a little high, aren't you?
当然
I sure am.
好了  你们想知道我的净资产
There. You wanted you wanted to know my net worth.
就是这个了
You got it.
-天呐  -你是谁啊
- Holy shit. - Who are you?
-你是国王吗  -不  我只是不傻
- Are you a king? - No, I'm just not an idiot.
你们都拿钱干什么了
What the hell have you been doing with your money?
路易  我们也不是穷人
Louis, we're not exactly poor.
那是玻利维亚跟英国说的话
That's what Bolivia says to the U.S.,
可一旦北约开战  他们完全没用
but if NATO goes to war, they're not kicking in dick.
如果你这么有钱
Well, if you're so damn rich, why didn't you pony up
当初有机会的时候为什么不付唐娜的工资
for Donna's salary when you had the chance?
你知道"财务责任"这个词怎么拼吗
Do you even know how to spell "Fiscal responsibility"?
我知道怎么拼"小气"
I know how to spell "Cheap."
好了  够了
All right, that's enough.
至少现在我们知道
At least now we know
我们有足够的钱来支持一阵了
we have enough to fund ourselves for a while.
你俩有有钱叔叔吗
You guys have two rich uncles?
因为如果这律所倒了  我是不会支撑你俩的
'Cause I'm not carrying your asses if this thing drags out.
路易  这是团队合作  而且我对上帝发誓
Louis, this is a team effort, and I swear to God,
如果你不帮我们
if you don't come through on this--
我不愿打扰你们的"早餐俱乐部"活动
I hate to interrupt your "Breakfast Club" Moment,
但你们得清醒一下
but you need to sober up.
-唐娜  怎么了  -据本杰明说
- Donna, what is it? - According to Benjamin,
合伙人们不光是走了
the partners didn't just leave.
他们还在挖我们所有客户墙角
They're coming after every client we have.
好  告诉我最新情况
All right, give me an update
用最简单的英语
and give it to me in plain English.
我找到了办法中断了黑客攻击
I was able to shut the hack down,
但没能赶在他们拿到三个你们的客户资料之前
but not before they got all three of your clients' files.
该死  他们要今晚就搞垮我们
Shit, they're trying to put us in the ground tonight.
那我们要在这事开始之前就阻止他们
Then we have to stop it before it even gets started.
唯一的问题是
Well, the only problem with that
我们不知道他们现在在外面
is that we don't know what bullshit story
到处宣扬什么说法
they're out there selling right now.
那我们得想办法知道  还得快
Then we need to figure it out. We need to figure it out fast.
是主线
It's the main line.
我们怎么办
What should we do?
唐娜
Donna.
皮-斯-利律所  有什么可以帮您
Pearson Specter Litt, may I help you?
请稍等
One moment, please.
找你的  吉姆・雷诺兹
It's for you. It's Jim Reynolds.
是德克尔制药  别接  他要离开
That's Decker Pharmaceutical. Don't take it. He's leaving us.
路易  他是我最老的客户
Louis, he's my oldest client.
我不能躲他的电话
I'm not ducking his call.
-杰西卡  -开免提
- Jessica. - Put him on speaker.
吉姆  有什么要我帮忙吗
Jim, how can I help you?
你可以跟我说说到底什么情况
You can tell me what's going on there.
我听说了很多流言
I've been hearing a lot of rumors,
我需要听你说实话
and I need to hear the truth from you.
好的吉姆  你想听事实是吗
All right, Jim, you want to hear the truth?
我们下午出去了一趟  回来的时候
We went out for the afternoon, and when we got back,
所有合伙人都不见了
every partner in the place was gone.
但我跟你说
But I'm telling you,
冠名合伙人还都在
the name partners are still here,
而我们依然可以为你和董事会服务
and we can still service you and the board.
我知道你可以
I know you can.
那你打来不是跟我们说要走的吗
Then you're not calling to say that you're leaving us?
我来告诉你  我收到了通告
I was calling to tell you I've been sent notice.
他们在拆解你的律所
They're bifurcating your firm,
而其他合伙人跟皮-斯-利律所
and the other partners have nothing to do
再没有关系了
with Pearson Specter Litt anymore.
谢谢  吉姆  我跟感激  也不会忘记这份情
Thanks, Jim. I appreciate it, and I won't forget it.
杰西卡  如果你在月末时
Jessica, if you're not back on your feet
没能站稳脚跟
by the end of the month,
我就拦不住董事会了
I won't be able to hold off the board.
如果我们在月末时没能站稳脚跟
If we're not back by the end of the month,
我会亲自打给董事会引咎辞职
I will call the board and resign from service myself.
这不是好事吗  他们没想要趁机占便宜
Isn't this good? They're not trying to poach.
-是坏事  -什么意思
- It's just as bad. - What do you mean?
这意味着他们现在已经不在乎客户了
It means they don't care about clients right now.
他们在拆解律所
They're bifurcating the firm
是因为他们想拿回合伙人的买入金
because they want their buy-ins back.
他们黑进我们的电脑获取客户信息
And they hacked us to get our clients' information
这样他们就能发布通告
so that they could deliver notice.
我们得在明天之前转移
We need to move the money that we have
所有账户里的钱
in every account by tomorrow.
我们用不着转移  我们得利用它们
We don't need to move it. We need to use it.
如果你在想我认为你在想的事
If you're thinking what I think you're thinking,
那你真是天才
you're a genius.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
我们可以用他们的钱
We can use their buy-ins
和解公司所面临的集体诉讼
to settle the class-action lawsuits.
然后他们就不能要回所有的钱
And they won't be able to sue us for the money back
因为钱已经没了
because it'll already be gone.
你真的是个天才
You really are a genius.
谢谢  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
我还是强调一下我才是那个
Uh, might I point out that I was the one
一开始让你们注意到公司系统
that brought the hacking to your attention
被黑这件事  所以...
in the first place, so...
还是告诉我你在想什么吧
You might as well tell me what's on your mind.
我在这里都可以感觉到
I can hear you staring at the wall
你一直盯着墙
from all the way over here.
你怎么解决的...
How do you handle it...
离开詹妮弗这么久
Being away from Jennifer for so long?
相信对方  探望对方
Trust each other, visit each other,
不问你不想知道答案的问题
and don't ask questions you don't want answers to.
听起来挺难的
That doesn't sound like fun.
不过对你来说应该没那么难吧
Yeah, well, it shouldn't be that hard for you.
你才进来待两年
You're only here for two years.
我还要待五年
I'm here for five more.
-天哪  -还用你说
- Jesus. - You're telling me.
也许我该给瑞秋发条短信
You know, maybe I'll just send Rachel a text...
让她知道我没事
you know, let her know that I'm okay.
当然的  孩子
Sure thing, kid.
发完了就还给我
Just give it back when you're done.
既然我们要重新开始
Well, now that we're starting fresh,
能不能把那副丑鸭画拿下来
can we please finally get rid of that hideous duck painting?
-不行  路易  -为什么不行
- No, Louis, we can't. - Why not?
因为它就像是你
Because it's like you.
虽然让人受不了  但终究是家人
I can't stand it, but it's part of the family.
说起家人  格蕾琴去哪了
Speaking of family, where's Gretchen?
我不敢相信她也抛下了我们
I can't believe she would walk out on us too.
她没有  本来今天我们要去参加婚礼
She didn't. We were supposed to be at the wedding,
所以我放她假让她去看正齿医生了
so I gave her the day off to go to the orthodontist.
-正齿医生吗  -是啊  她都60多了
- Orthodontist? - Yeah, the woman's in her 60s.
还带着牙套
She still wears a retainer.
好了  计划是这样
All right, we have a game plan.
明天早上我们
Tomorrow morning, we offer them
拿出十分之一的钱摆平集体诉讼
ten cents on the dollar to settle these suits.
从现在开始
And from this point on,
我们都要为了这个公司
we are all committing to giving this firm
拼尽全力
every ounce of blood, sweat, and tears we have.
什么
What is it?
我刚收到了一条迈克的短信
I just got a text from Mike.
怎么说的
What does it say?
他说他安顿了下来
It says that he's settling in
然后他和室友相处很融洽
and that he's getting along well with his roommate...
还有他说他会没事的
And that he thinks he's gonna be okay.
也许他是会没事
Maybe he's gonna be okay,
但他室友就有麻烦了
but his roommate's in for trouble.
敬麻烦
To trouble.
什么
What?
她回你短信了
She texted you back.
她说什么
What did she say?
她说她收到了你的短信  她很想你
She says she got your text, she misses you,
还有她很高兴你和室友相处融洽
And she's glad you get along with your roomate.
谢谢你  弗兰克
Thanks, Frank.
谢谢你做的一切
For everthing.
好了  走吧
All right, let's go.
快  你得在下一班查房之前离开
Come on, you got to get out before next shift.
换房的事不能让他们发现
They can't know I let you switch.
等等  换什么
Wait, switch what?
这就是我的牢房  你们给我的牢房
I'm in the right cell. I'm in the one you gave me.
是啊  但这不是他们给我的房间
Yeah, but this isn't the one they gave me.
什么
What?
这是你的房间  但不是我的
You're in the right cell. I'm not.
你到底在说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
今晚我告诉你的唯一一件真事
Only thing I told you tonight that's true
是你不能相信这里的任何人
is that you shouldn't trust people in here.
但是你信了  现在我知道了你的一切
But you did. Now I know all about you.
你为何要这样做
Why the hell would you do that to me?
你说你本来你可以让另一个人进来的
You said you could've turned on a guy to get out of here
但是你没有因为你觉得自己亏欠他
but you didn't because you owe him.
好吧  我也欠那个够娘养的
Well, I owe that son of bitch too.
-哈维  -是啊  哈维・斯佩克特
- Harvey.  - Yeah, Harvy Specter.
13年前送我进了这里
Put me away 13 years ago.
自那以后我做梦都想报复他
I've been dreaming about getting him back ever since.
然后我在报纸上看到了你
Then I read about you in the paper.
我意识到
I realized that
即使不出监狱我也可以报仇
I could get back at him without leaving these walls.
混蛋
You son of bitch.
放松  迈克
Get it easy, Mike.
记得我知道你的一切
You remember I know about you.
还有你女朋友的电话号码
And I get your little girlfriend's number right here.